

Michelle Griffith

Data Scientist

+17208837265 michellemg91@gmail.com Linkedin | Github

I'm a versatile Data Scientist with machine learning, data analysis, statistical modeling, and visualization expertise. I specialize in building analyses and models that translate data into actionable business insights. I aim to drive measurable impacts in a mission-driven organization and grow as a leader in the field.

Languages and Tools

- Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Beautiful Soup, and more)
- SQL (PostgreSQL, Snowflake)
- dbt (data modeling, ELT)

Machine Learning

- Scikit-learn (machine learning)
- PyTorch (deep learning)
- spaCy, NLTK, gensim (NLP)

Data Visualization

- Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Dashboarding (Sigma)

Cloud Computing

- GCP (Vertex AI, BigQuery)
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Education

Bachelor of Science, Engineering Physics Colorado School of Mines

2010-2014, GPA 3.6, Cum Laude Mu Alpha Theta Mathematics Honor Society

Data Science Certificate, 2020-2021

<u>Thinkful / Chegg Skills</u>

<u>Select Projects available on Github</u>

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Divvy Homes

San Francisco | Feb 2022 - Sept 2023

Data Scientist I and II

- Enhanced customer acquisition by developing a machine learning model for lead scoring, improving targeting based on conversion likelihood.
- Developed composite model pipelines using AutoML in GCP's VertexAl for asset LTV prediction, enhancing business decisions and ROI.
- Created benchmark data models using dbt, achieving over 50% increase in data field coverage by consolidating multiple sources.
- Conducted regular ad hoc analyses of customer and asset data and other company metrics.

Maxar Technologies

Westminster, CO | May 2021 - Feb 2022

AWS Cloud Support Engineer

- Responded to and directed AWS-related tech support tickets from the entire company
- Specialized in AWS resource compliance and optimization, utilizing boto for automated fixes.

Independent Business Owner

Moab, UT | Jan 2015 - Dec 2019

Self Employed in the Outdoor and Wellness Industry

- Successfully led and marketed <u>Wild Sol Retreats</u>, offering unforgettable off-grid adventure retreats.
- Foundational leadership and programming director for GGBY, an internationally acclaimed annual outdoor adventure festival in Moab, UT
- Received global certifications in slacklining, yoga, and partner acrobatics
- Taught internationally at the prestigious <u>Wanderlust Yoga</u>
 Festival

National Renewable Energy Laboratory

Golden, CO | May 2011 - Sept 2013

Photovoltaics Research Associate

- Conducted research to improve Cadmium Telluride (CdTe) solar cell efficiency. The publication can be found here.
- Fabricated CdTe solar cells using sputtering techniques.
- Analyzed and optimized the Cadmium Sulfide layer for peak CdTe cell performance.

Industry Growth Forum Staff, Business Pitch Counselor

- Conducted market research on emerging cleantech startups.
- Advised cleantech startups on pitches and funding at the Industry Growth Forum, driving record attendance for two consecutive years.